Tony Hinton

Microsoft Software Engineer

Gilbert, AZ - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Tony-Hinton/4f6c4440ed9464f1

Gilbert, AZ Mobile [...] Kajukenbodojo@gmail.com

Summary:

25 years of application development, web application, software architect, technical lead and database development experience primary with the latest releases of Microsoft technologies. Experience working in different development cultures from two person projects to a team of 450 developers on the same project. Working with various development SDLC methodologies, methods, patterns and processes. Considered by my employers and clients as a top-performer.

Current Technical Skills, Methodologies and Compliance standards:

MVC 4x, MVC 5x, C#, Object Oriented coding, Coding with Patterns, Net, Microsoft Visual Studio [...] Team Foundation Server Admin 2015, Rally, Jira, XML, AJAX, Web Services, Web API, Angular, LINQ, JavaScript, MS SQL Server 2008 [...] Entity Framework 5x/6x, ReSharper, Red Gate, HTML 4/5, CSS, XHTML, Agile methods (XP, SCRUM), MVC 4x/5x, Dependency Injection, Unity, Microsoft Enterprise Library, Open XML, Closed XML, SSIS, Swift, iOS development, Xcode.

Prior Technical Skills, Methodologies and Compliance standards:

Microsoft Visual Studio [...] Team Foundation Server 2010, GOOGLE ANALYTICS, XSD, XSLT, VB Script, C/C++ Microsoft and Borland, MASM 6.11, Subversion, Tortoise, MS SQL Server [...] SSIS, DTS, SSRS, fluent n-hibernate, UML, SharePoint [...] XPO Persistence layer, automation scripting languages, PHP, REXX, International application development, Sarbanes-Oxley (SOX) compliance, HIPAA compliant, Waterfall SDLC Method.

Education

- BS/Information Technology 2004 3.72 GPA
- Arizona State University
- University of Phoenix
- Oklahoma State University

Technical Certifications:

- Microsoft Certified Systems Engineer
- Microsoft Certified Professional
- Microsoft Certified Solutions Developer
- Microsoft Certified Trainer
- Federal Contractor Security Clearance

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

Blackhawk - Mesa, AZ - 2016 to Present

- Developed Back End software products in C# for B2B transactions.
- Excel Import and Export data to SQL using LINQ, EF, and C#.
- · Using Microsoft Enterprise Library for IOC, n-tier validation and logging.
- Maintained and developed new and existing web UI pages using legacy Web Forms
- Maintained existing web UI layers using Angular.

Software Developer

Venicom Inc - 2015 to 2016

- * Developed multiple software products in C# for the telecom industry.
- * Full development in pure agile with scrums using TFS 2015.
- * Developed new web applications in MVC 4 and MVC 5 in VS2013 and VS2015.
- * Maintained and developed new and existing web applications using legacy Web Forms.
- * Daily Sprints.
- * Wrote Entity Framework 5.x and 6.x to handle new web application calls to MSSQL 2008R2 and MSSQL 2014
- * Code reviews
- * Code promotion.
- * Wrote and consumed Web Services.

Software Developer

InData - 2014 to 2015

- * Developed Speech Recognition Software using C#
- * Used for DB Domain Entity Framework 4.x
- * Peer Software training
- * Code reviews
- * Daily Scrums
- * Coded with SOLID
- * Developed Legal Software with MVC 4.x

IT Manager

Garvin Promotions Group - 2013 to 2014

- * Software development and IT product design lifecycle
- * Delivering leading edge solutions that consistent meet complex and changing business requirements.
- * Built strong relationships with IT staff, customers, vendors and third party contractors.
- * Used my solid understand of application development, computer programming and architecture design.
- * Separated support tasks, and implementing best practices.
- * Initiatives to restructure software product development processes to increase productivity.

Software Developer for Corporate Tax Systems Development

First Advantage - 2010 to 2013

Migrated older systems and data to new technologies where appropriate.

- * Analyzed and made decisions on which applications to uplift / combine or rewrite based on aligning business requirements with best practice technologies to synthesize appropriate systems.
- * Designed TFS tracking templates for TFS 2010 for development team.
- * Designed and built new web based software applications as needed in VS 2010, VS2012

Software Developer

Veterans Administration - 2009 to 2010

- * My main project was designing and coding online training class education testing software to government certification standards for the Veterans Administration and C.M.S.
- * Other projects were to refactor the CMS code for the internal human resources web portal.
- * Migrated internal company CMS system to a new MOSS SharePoint 2007/2010. This involved both SharePoint administration and SharePoint development.
- * GOOGLE ANALYTICS, and Eblast marketing campaigns.
- * Developed code in C# 3.5 and C# 4.0 .Net frameworks 3.5 and 4.0. Used visual studio 2008 and 2010 beta 2 for all projects. For all projects used Team Foundation server.

Software Developer

Health Choice / IASIS Healthcare - 2006 to 2009

- * Developed and coded a new system based on Web Services (.Net 3.5, SQL Server 2005/2008, MVC) and Visual Studio 2008 to automate manual processes to online applications and uplift older applications on asp classic, VB Script, VB.NET, C# and earlier version of .NET to 3.5.
- * Trained staff on C# 3.0, XPO Persistence layer, Subversion, and implemented those standards for all applications. Implemented Agile development SCRUM.
- * Analyzed and supported the CMS DotNetNuke framework, developed standards, and migrated to a new MOSS SharePoint 2007 system.
- * Security audit of all applications and uplifted them to HIPAA compliance in all my C# and VB.Net coding.
- * Maintained existing application in VB.NET, classic ASP 3.0 and click once.
- * Architect and developer for C# and TSQL new data schema and the conversion from a legacy system to a web 2.0 system.
- * Created new DBs and stored procedures in MS SQL 2005, created new AJAX applications in C# VS .NET 2005, .NET framework 2.0

Software Engineer

IBM - Remote - April 1995 to March 2006

Traveled to on Fortune 100 companies as a software engineer consultant as a founding member of the CFMT, Consulting For Microsoft Technologies. Our team later became ESMT, Enterprise Services For Microsoft Technologies. I wrote only Microsoft code, IBM was trying out do business as a technology agnostic offering, which they have stayed with. Before us and our team, IBM was IBM technologies only.

Web Portal Application Developer

IBM - 2004 to 2006

- * System developer focusing on Applications and Security.
- * Worked on LEAN application development using the Xtreme programming agile software development SDLC.
- * Developed and coded a project management global portal (Visual Studio 2003/2005, .Net 2.0, SQL Server 2000, C#, PHP AJAX) that focused on timelines tracking progress and request for services.

- * Developed, coded, debugged and released in-house custom software applications and custom framework portals in C# and ASP .NET 1.1 and 2.0 using visual studio 2003/2005.
- * Designed SQL Enterprise Server 2000/2005 Data adapters, data schemas, ERDs, databases, functions, DTS packages, stored procedures and views.
- * Designed and developed Web Services in C#. Created, utilized and manipulated XML, XML Parsers in C ++, and XLST.

Software developer

IBM - 2002 to 2004

- * Lead I.T. Developer for offshore developers in Amex Travel. Coded C# and SQL to Sarbanes-Oxley (SOX) compliance of applications and American Express banking standards.
- * Creation and integration of applications (SQL, XML, .Net, BI, UML) with vendor applications.
- * Worked with the clients and vendors on the data migration project, which includes analyzing data, developing stored procedures and ERDs, and regulating compliance needs. Hands on coding in C# and TSQL.

Software Consultant/Developer

IBM - 1997 to 2002

- * Working with Enterprise Services for Microsoft Technologies division of IBM that specializes in developing solutions for Fortune 100 companies utilizing Microsoft technologies.
- * Application Development in VB6, VS97, and ASP 1.x-3.x of n-tier applications for the Internet and Intranets.
- * Application Development of enterprise applications.

Systems Administrator

IBM - 1996 to 1997

- * Served as a Network administrator for IBM Phoenix utilizing an NT and LAN server network.
- * Troubleshooting skills with network servers and client desktop systems.
- * Developed in house applications for network in REXX/C/C++. Including a network program to monitor all printers on the enterprise network. This earned an IBM award.

Systems Developer

IBM - 1995 to 1996

- * Designed, created and implemented applications for the standard helpdesk image.
- * Implemented, deployed, moved into production and maintained systems.

New Systems Integration Developer

Visa - 1991 to 1995

- * Application Development in assembler and C/C++ of in-house software. Including several programs VISA still uses today.
- * Support and integration of PC prototype banking software.
- * Developed banking call center support software.

EDUCATION

BS in Information Technology

Arizona State University 2004

University of Phoenix

Oklahoma State University

SKILLS

c# (10+ years), SQL (10+ years), Angular (1 year), Javascript (10+ years), MVC (4 years), Visual Studio (10+ years), Entity Framework (4 years), Web API (2 years), AJAX (7 years), Web Formss (10+ years)